A Finding Aid to the Diógenes Ballester papers, 1973-2020, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Diógenes Ballester papers
1973-2020
Archives of American Art
Ballester, Diógenes, 1956-
AAA.balldiog
Archival Resource Key
6 Linear feet
The papers of Diogenes Ballester measure 6.0 linear feet, and date from 1973 to 2020. The papers document his career as an artist, educator, and writer through correspondence with family friends, and various museums and galleries; notes, drafts of articles, drafts of lecture and presentation transcripts, and other writings; inventories, price lists, ledger books, and other personal business records; resumes, artist statements, exhibition files, and other professional activity files; clippings, articles, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and other printed material; and photographs and slides of Ballester, some of his family and friends, and of some of his artwork.
Biographical / Historical
Diógenes Ballester (1956- ) is an artist based in New York City, with deep roots in Puerto Rico, where he is also regularly present. His studio in El Barrio has operated since 1987 and he is a prominent artist, teacher, and writer particularly in Puerto Rican and Nuyorican artistic communities.
Ballester works in different artistic media including painting, printmaking, drawing, new media, and installation art and is recognized as a master of encaustic painting and printmaking. He has received numerous honors for his artistic work and has exhibited widely in the United States, Europe, Asia, Latin America and the Caribbean.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into six series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1984-2016 (0.5 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 2: Writings, 1983-2020 (0.9 linear feet; Boxes 1-2)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, 1983-2018 (0.4 linear feet; Box 2)
Series 4: Professional Activity Files, 1973-2018 (2.5 linear feet; Boxes 2-5)
Series 5: Printed Material, 1975-2020 (1.1 linear feet; Boxes 5-6)
Series 6: Photographic Material, circa 1990-2011 (0.6 linear feet; Box 6)
Scope and Contents
The papers of Diogenes Ballester measure 6.0 linear feet, and date from 1973 to 2020. The papers document his career as an artist, educator, and writer through correspondence with family and friends, and various museums and galleries; notes, drafts of articles, drafts of lecture and presentation transcripts, and other writings; inventories, price lists, ledger books, and other personal business records; resumes, artist statements, exhibition files, and other professional activity files; clippings, articles, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and other printed material; and photographs and slides of Ballester, some of his family and friends, and of some of his artwork.
Correspondence includes letters from his wife, Maria Boncher, artist Marshall Weber, cover letters, letter of recommendation, and letters with various museums and galleries. Also included is a booklet of letters and drawings from students at Project YES, an arts program for children.
Writings include drafts for articles written by Ballester, articles written by Shifra Goldman, drafts for a book on Ballester and drafts lectures and presentations given by Ballester. Also included are a number of notepads and miscellaneous notes.
Personal business records consist of inventories and price lists, invoices, two ledger books, copies of checks and receipts, and proposals and blueprints for the establishment of an artist-in-residency program in Puerto Rico.
Professional activity files consist of exhibitions that Ballester participated in at various biennials in graphic arts around the world. Some of these locations include San Juan, Puerto Rico; Krakow, Poland; and Taipei. Among the materials on biennials are a number of files pertaining to the San Juan Biennial on Printmaking from 1986 to 2010. These files contain lecture transcripts, clippings, articles by Ballester and others, draft exhibition catalogs, and notes. Also included are some exhibition files for exhibitions held at museums in the United States, proposals for exhibitions, artist statements, resumes, and binders documenting his professional career. The binders contain resumes, artist statements and narratives, some exhibition announcements and press releases, and photographs of artwork. Also included are some sketches by Ballester.
Printed material consists of articles on and written by Ballester, clippings, newsletters, exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, press releases, and posters.
Photographic material consists of photographs of Ballester, photographs of Ballester with friends and family, photographs of an exhibition, and photographs and slides of artwork.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Researchers interested in accessing born-digital records in this collection must use access copies. Contact References Services for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated in 2022 by Diógenes Ballester.
Latino and Latin American artists; Artists -- New York (State) -- New York; Artists -- Puerto Rico; Graphic artists -- New York (State) -- New York; Educators -- New York (State) -- New York
- Correspondence, 1984-2016; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence includes letters from his wife, Maria Boncher, artist Marshall Weber, cover letters, letter of recommendation, and letters with various museums and galleries. Also included is a booklet of letters and drawings from students at Project YES, an arts program for children.
  - "Abstracciones de Retratos y Alegorias" Exhibition, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Marini Acin, 1997-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Maria Boncher, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cover Letters, 1990-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A-C, 1994-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - D-I, 1986-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Zhao Jiachun, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1987-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Andres Marrero, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - J-O, 1987-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Project YES, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - P-T, 1985-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Marshall Weber, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - U-Z, 1991-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1984-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
- Writings and Lectures, 1983-2020; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 0.9 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Writings include drafts for articles written by Ballester, articles written by Shifra Goldman, drafts for a book on Ballester and drafts lecures and presentations given by Ballester. Also included are a number of notepads and miscellaneous notes.
  - "Aesthetic Development of Puerto Rican Visual Arts in New York as Part of the Diaspora: The Epitaph of the Barrio" by Ballester, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lecture, "Art and Healing", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Articles by Ballester, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Lecture, "Diogenes Ballester: Collective Memories of the Syncretic Experience", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Between "Aca" and "Alla": Thirty Years of Taller Boriqua" by Shifra M. Goldman, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Draft, Book on Ballester, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21-25)
  - "Confessions", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Diogenes: Engraver" by Cirilo Toro Vargas, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Diogenes Ballester: Collective Memories of Syncretic Experiences" by Maria Boncher and Diogenes Ballester, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Versions in both English and Spanish present.
  - "Diogenes Ballester: Las Raices Ancestrales de la Historia del Silencio", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Diogenes Ballester: Seeking Artistic and Creative Transnationalism" by Shifra M. Goldman, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - El Taller Boriqua Essay Notes, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Encuentros con la Madama: Mitologia y Realidad en la Obra de Diogenes Ballester" by Francisco Sorribes Vaca, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Lecture, "Graphic Language in the Development of Individual and Collective Latino Identity", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - Lectures and Speeches, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Lecture, "Los Muelleros: Historia de la Playa de Ponce" by Mary Boncher, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Mensaje de la Conferencia Episcopal Puertorriqueno, 2016 October 10; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Lecture, Museo de Historia, Antropologia y Arte, 2020; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Lecture, "Newyorican Manifestation", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40-42)
  - Note Cards, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Notebook, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Notepad, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Notepad, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Notepad, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Lecture, "Diogenes Ballester: Manifesto of an Arteologist", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Draft, "Pintura y Utopia en Diogenes Ballester" by Francisco Sorribes, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Outline for Presentation for Library of Congress, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Poems, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Presentation at Medianoche Gallery, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Puerto Rican Artists, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Puerto Rican for Independence, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Lecture, "Reconfigured Perspective: History of a Memory", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
  - Lecture, "Restos: Estudio Arteologico", 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Shifra M. Goldman on Ballester, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Taina B. Caragol Barreto Dissertation Proposal, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Lecture, "Thoughts About the Aesthetics of Jorge Soto Sanchez", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Panel, "Visual Art: A Method of Cultural Communication and Education in the Era of New Technology", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Electronic discs (CD) (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
    Disc is labeled, "LASA 25 Slides Presentation"
- Personal Business Records, 1983-2018; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 2
  Personal business records consist of inventories and price lists, invoices, two ledger books, copies of checks and receipts, and proposals and blueprints for the establishment of an artist-in-residency program in Puerto Rico.
  - Artist Residency, Renovations, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Business Plan, 2011 June; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Certificates of Authenticity, 2013, 2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Checks and Receipts, 1989-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - Galerias Prinardi Consignment, 1999-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Inventory and Price Lists, 1983-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24-26)
  - Invoices, 2013-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
  - Ledger Book, 1983-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Ledger Notebook, 2010-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Merchant Registration Certificate, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Proposal, National and International Artist-In-Residence and Cultural Exchange of La Playa de Ponce, Puerto Rico, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Proposal, Sale of Artwork, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Receipts, Coronado Print Studio, 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Receipts, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Request for Check Payments, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Professional Activity Files, 1973-2018; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 2-5
  Professional activity files consist of exhibitions that Ballester participated in at various biennials in graphic arts around the world. Some of these locations include San Juan, Puerto Rico, Krakow, Poland, and Taipei. Among the materials on biennials are a number of files pertaining to the San Juan Biennial on Printmaking from 1986 to 2010. These files contain lecture transcripts, clippings, articles by Ballester and others, draft exhibition catalogs, and notes. Also included are some exhibition files for exhibitions held at museums in the United States, proposals for exhibitions, artist statements, resumes, and binders documenting his professional career. The binders contain resumes, artist statements and narratives, some exhibition announcements and press releases, and photographs of artwork. Also included are some sketches by Ballester.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged for the most part in alphabetical order with the exception being files related to the San Juan Biennials wich are at the end of the series.
  - 3rd International Biennial Print Exhibit, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 4th Beijing International Art Biennale, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 9th International Biennial Print and Drawing Exhibition, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 10th Biennial Print and drawing Exhibition, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - 10th International Taipei Biennial, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 16th International Biennial of Graphic Art, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - 27th Salon International del Val D'or, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - 40th Anniversary International Print Triennial of Crackow, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Address Lists, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Advanced Opportunity Fellowship, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - "Akashic Archives" Carter Burden Gallery, 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Art 306: Workshop in Drawing, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Artist Statements, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50-52)
  - "Artists Talk Back: Visual Conversations with El Museo, Part III: Reaffirming Spirituality" Exhibition, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Binder, "Art-Projects Time of Departure: Post Syncretism Drawing and Painting Installations", 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Binder, Professional Documentation, 1978, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Binder, Professional Documentation, 1984-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Binder, Professional Documentation, 1991-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Binder, Professional Documentation, 1995-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Binder, Professional Documentation, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Black Madonna Information, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Bronx Museum of Arts, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Byrdcliffe Arts Colony, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Certificate, 6th International Biennial Print & Drawing Exhibit, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Calendar Book, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Calendar Book, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Calendar Book, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Calendar Book, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Calendar Book, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Calendar Book, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Caribbean Fine Arts Fair, 2014-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Caribbean Visions: Contemporary Painting and Sculpture" Exhibition, 1994-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Certificate of Merit, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "Chicanos, Puertorriquenos and Latinos in the Arts: A Heritage Celebrated" Exhibition, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - College Transcripts, 1973-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "Confesiones Ancestrales: Evidencia Historica de una Ciudad Pinturas/Intalaciones/Transmissiones Ciberneticas" Exhibition, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - "Confesiones de Diogenes Ballester" Video Conference Materials, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Courses Syllabi, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Decima Exposicion de Arte Poceno, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "Diogenes Ballester" Exhibtiion, Banco Financiero, Ponce, Puerto Rico, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "Diogenes Ballester: L'Energie de la Terre" Exhibition, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Diogenes Ballester: Registro Libre: Encuentro, Mitologia y Realidad" Exhibition, 2007-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27-28)
  - "El Barrio Artists Network" Exhibition, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "Emerging Expression: The Artist and the Computer" Exhibition, Bronx Museum of the Arts, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - "Encounter of Artists and Critics of American and Africa: Identity and Diversity versus New Milenio", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Proposal, "Encounter with the Madama: Re-Affirming Our Roots", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Evaluation, Juan Sanchez for MacArthur Fellowship, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Floppy Disk, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Floppy disc (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Disk is unlabeled.
  - Project Proposal, "Free Registry: Encounter: Mythology and Reality", circa 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Forum Multiculturel d'Art Contemporain, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Fundacion Alfonso Arana, 1997-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
  - Galeria Botello, 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Gottlieb Foundation Grant, 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Guanlan International Print Biennial, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Guestbook, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Guestbook, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - IMDC Video Distribution, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Interchurch Center, 2013, 2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Intergrafik 87, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - International Art Critics Association Southern Caribbean 2001 Symposium, University of Central Florida, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 47-49)
  - "Intimidad de la Memoria" Exhibition, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Teaching, Joan Mitchell Foundation Inc., circa 2000-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Project: Latin American Graphics: The Evolution of Identity From the Mythical to the Personal, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Leonardo Sciascia Prize Amateur d'Estampes, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Loan Agreements, 2015, 2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Los Leones de Ponce" Sculpture Project, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - LMCC Artist Residencies and Grants, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - El Museo del Barrio, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Nu-YO-Rican" Exhibition, Hunter College East Harlem Art Gallery, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "On and Off the Wall: An Aljira Salon" Exhibition, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Passport and Marriage License, 1987-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Pontifical Catholic University of Puerto Rico Certificate, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Professional Activity Folder, circa 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Proposals, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Project Proposal, Aldrich Contemporary Art Museum, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Proposal for Book Portfolio, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Proposal for an Exhibition of Diogenes Ballester at Carib Art Gallery, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Printmaking Workshop, Blackburn, 1982-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Resumes, 1986-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20-22)
  - "Scared Altars" Exhibition, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Serie Project Inc., 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Sketches, circa 2008-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25-28)
  - Reproductions, Sketches, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Staff Meetings Notes, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - State University of New York at Albany Teaching Position, 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Teaching, Student Submitted Assignments, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - "The Struggle" Master of Fine Arts Exhibition, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Tai Chi & QiGong Class, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - "Tattwa: El Ritmo de la Vida" Exhibition, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Teaching, Art 012Z CEA - Fundamentals of Painting, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Trienal Poli/Grafica de San Juan: America Latina y el Caribe, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - University of Notre Dame Visit, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - University of Wisconsin-Madison, Graduate Studies Material, 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - University of Wisconsin Teaching Position, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Wax Acrylic Art Print Making, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - San Juan Biennial, Archival Resource Key
    - Project Proposal, Bienal de San Juan del Grabado Latinoamericano y del Caribe, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - 13th Biennial San Juan, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Alicia Candiani, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Articles, 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
    - Clippings, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Essay Drafts, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Exhibition of Welcome to the VII Latin American and Caribbean Biennial of San Juan, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - "Hacia un Nuevo Entendimiento de la Experiencia Artistica" by Francisco Jose Ramos, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - List of Works Accepted, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 51-52)
    - Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 53)